<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!--Notes to self
Consider standardizing more stuff. In vanilla, nuclear stomach causes cancer/120 days, smokeleaf every 180-130 days, toxic buildup 111 days

For bicompatability mods: Royalty + CommunicableDiseases, the patch goes in the smaller mod.
-->
<ModMetaData>
	<name>Primum Medicine</name>
	<author>Nooberthetuber</author>
	<supportedVersions>
		<li>1.3</li>
	</supportedVersions>
	<packageId>primum.medicine</packageId>
	<modDependencies>
		<li>
			<packageId>brrainz.harmony</packageId>
			<displayName>Harmony</displayName>
			<steamWorkshopUrl>steam://url/CommunityFilePage/2009463077</steamWorkshopUrl>
			<downloadUrl>https://github.com/pardeike/HarmonyRimWorld/releases/latest</downloadUrl>
		</li>
	</modDependencies>
	<loadAfter>
		<li>brrainz.harmony</li>
		<li>Ludeon.Rimworld.Royalty</li>
		<li>Ludeon.Rimworld.Ideology</li>
		<li>ONegative.CommunicableDiseases</li>
	</loadAfter>
	<description>
		Stages:
			A: in process of implementing
			B: implemented, needs testing
			C: finished
			?: Possible future addition
		Adjusts medical features within Rimworld while staying as true to vanilla as possible
B			Luciferium: prevents drug overdose
?			Penoxycycline: more immunities? Probably already good enough, plus tuberculosis is resistant to most antibiotics
?			Trauma savant: expanded
?			Traits: Superimmune to 1.2 immune factor, sickly to disease/2 years
?		Adds new organs and adjusts existing organs
			Vanilla bionics also add ??? in order to make body-purity make a little more sense.
			Compatability with Rah's bionics
		Adds new diseases and adjusts existing ones
			Disease principles:
				T_D (Tending difficulty is minimum q so that immunity catches up: n = i*s + t*q. q = (n-i*s)/t
				N_C (natural course or time to death untreated) = 1/n
				I_F (how much each increment by 1 of immunity gain speed affects tending difficulty) = dq/ds = -i/t
				s = immunity gain speed (assumed 1)
				q = average tending quality (assume = tending difficulty, T_D). 
				n = severity not immune per day = 1/N_C = i + t*T_D
				i = immunity per day = (n - t*q)/s = 1/N_C - t*T_D = 1/N_C + i*T_D/I_F = 1/N_C / (1 + T_D/I_F)
				t = severity tended per day = -i/I_F
				n_maxfactor = (i + t*T_D_max)/n
				
				Stages: (general guideline, not always; vanilla is a little more extreme, but this works for me.)
					0-0.5 = minor 
					0.5-0.8 = major
					0.8-1 = extreme

		  
		  
			Tumors
B				Carcinoma: Spreads, may cause secondary damage, stroke, heart attack. Increased psychic sensitivity. T_D = 0.7-1.7
B				Leukemia: Growth/remission like carcinoma; causes stroke, heart attack. Difficult to treat. Increased psychic sensitivity. T_D = 1-2
B				Fibroma: Benign growth that acts like vanilla cancer.
				
			Infectious:
B				Gut worm: may cause cirrhosis
B				Muscle parasites: may cause frailty
B				Brain worm: may cause dementia
B				Lung worm: may cause gut worm, asthma
				
C				Flu: N_C = 4, I_F = 3.1, T_D = 0.13. No changes
B				Plague: N_C = 1.5, I_F = 1.44, T_D = 0.4, fibromas, necrosis
B				Malaria: N_C = 2.7, I_F = 1.36, T_D = 0.24, encapsulation, cirrhosis
B				Sleeping sickness: N_C = 8.33, I_F = 1.43, T_D = 0.29 causes coma
B				Wound infection: N_C = 1.2, I_F = 1.22, T_D = 0.37 causes sepsis.
B				Tuberculosis: N_C = 6, I_F = 4.5, T_D = 0.2, encapsulation, bad_back. Rare-ish
B	R			Blood rot: N_C = 2.5, T_D = 0.4-0.7. Can be caught normally. Rare. Promotes cancer/leukemia.
?	R			Imperial rot: N_C = 4, T_D = 0.7
					Imperial rot was originally developed by the Empire as a biological weapon to control their less civilized foes, but was replaced with Blood rot when imperial rot was found to have... unanticipated side effects.
					Something similar to vampirism. Chance to confer "the long rot", which slowly gives heightened abilities in exchange for exclusive subsistence on human flesh versus impaired immune ability?
			Chronic
B				Artery blockage that can happen in the brain as well as the heart. Angioplasty to remove.
B				Cirrhosis: predisposes to liver carcinoma
?				Migraine: increased psychic sensitivity. Occasional migraine attack (mild or severe) that lasts 6-12 hours)
?				Asthma: may progress to status asthmaticus
?	VCE			Cholesterol: risk of heart artery blockage
?	VCE			High blood pressure: risk of brain artery blockage
?	VCE			Diabetes: waxing/waning disease like cancer
			Acute (don't really know how to work with acute condition code, so most of these won't be realized)
B				Stroke: Heart attack for the brain. Cause secondary damage, dementia
B				Heart attacks: cause necrosis, secondary damage
?				Status asthmaticus
			Secondary
B				Sepsis 0.4-0.9
B				Necrosis: Dead tissues within an organ; grows and causes sepsis. No tending possible; must be excised
B				Secondary damage (chemical damage will only be used by mods I don't incorporate, represents both ischemia, severe tissue stress, and chemical damage)
					mild: Recovers on its own in 30-90 days. Cut down to 15 days with good treatment
					moderate: N_C 45, T_D 0.2
					severe: N_C 30-90 like moderate, but tend difficulty 0.8
B				Coma: untendable, lasts 0.33-3 years. May attempt to cure with glitterworld medicine.
?				ImmuneExhaustion: increases vulnerability to opportunistic disease following severe bodily strain
B				Encapsulation (may remove with antibiotic infusion; 0.25 potential for mild pain). For Malaria, Tuberculosis
			HediffGiver and EnvironmentEvent
B				So new diseases can be fully integrated into the game on an ongoing basis.
?			Mental
				PTSD
				Schizophrenia
				Depression
				Bipolar
?			Congenital
		Adds new surgeries and standardizes existing ones
			Formatted as skill/success_chance/death_chance. Surgeries with >10 skill require non-herbal medicine
?			Surgery standards
				Brain surgery = 16/0.9/.4
				Archotech/Carcioma/angioplasty = 13/1/.3
				Necrosis/fibroma/pathogens = 10/1/.2
				Drug administration/mechanite infusion = 7/1.25/.1
				Amputation = 4/1.5/0
		Makes surgery behave more reasonably
			If you have a surgery that requires 13 skill, then a surgeon with 20 skill should be way better at in than a surgeon with 13.
			
			Cleanliness (c): varies from ~-10 to 0.6
				C = 0.6 +(0.9 * (c+5)/10), in range [0.6, 1.5]
				At cleanliness 0.6, this factor is 1.1
			Medical potency (M): varies from 70% to 160%
			Doctor's success factor (d) varies from 0.05 to 1.1 at skill 0 to 20. Additionally influenced by traits
				D = d
			Bed success chance factor (B) varies from 0.9 (awful bed) to 1.48 (legendary medical bed with vitals monitor)
			
			Default formula
				P(success) = C*M*D*B
			New formula
				P(success) = (C*M*D*B * E^2)^(1/6)
					Geometric mean, with E having extra weightMakes it regress toward the lowest factor
					If P>0.95, P = 0.95 + (P-0.95)/5. That last 5% success rate is hard to get.
					Note that in the code, B and C are mixed together. Cleanliness is still a factor!
				D adjusted to not depend on doctor's skill. Examples include: Inspiration = 2, also increases effective skill by 4 for E calculation, Mad surgeon (VTE) = 1.2, and Medical specialist (ideology) = 1.5. Only dependent on traits, inspiration, etc. This is accomplishd by a patch to stats_pawns_workmedical
				E is max(1,0.4+0.6*(SurplusSkill/5))

			
		Includes compatability with other mods
B			Royalty
B			CommunicableDiseases: tuberculosis, blood rot spread germs
?			Vanilla Cooking Expanded
			
	</description>
</ModMetaData>